RACHEL KOLDENHOVEN

303.909.6793
rachel@koldenfrozen.com
linkedin.com/in/koldenfrozen
www.koldenfrozen.com

SUMMARY

I strive to create business value by continuously delivering quality software as part of a collaborative team. I utilize my education experience to facilitate knowledge transfer in development teams and promote an environment of continual learning.

SKILLS

JavaScript	TypeScript	React	Redux/Toolkit	Jest, Cypress
CSS/SCSS	MQTT	Segment Analytics	Tweek feature toggles	Accessibility

WORK EXPERIENCE

WORK Software Developer, Poppulo (formerly Four Winds Interactive)

July 2019 - present

Front end developer creating new features with TypeScript and React

Accomplishments

- Build and maintain shared component library
- Implement new features in Poppulo Harmony Device Management module
- Facilitate the Tech Learning Series, helping colleagues to share their technical skills across three acquired companies
- Onboarding and mentoring of new developers
- As a member of the DEI&B council, facilitated monthly Knowledge Series discussions

Lead Enterprise Instructor, Galvanize, Inc.

November 2018 - June 2019

Lead education of new hires and reskilling of existing employees, preparing them to join agile product teams

Accomplishments

- Assess health of XP product teams by analyzing test coverage and quality, team workflow, and CI/CD practices to provide recommendations to improve continuous delivery of quality software
- Guide 34 developers to incept and build an MVP consensus-building app using TDD and Heroku flow
- Onboarding and mentoring of new instructors

Associate Enterprise Instructor, Galvanize, Inc.

October 2017 - October 2018

Facilitate learning for software developers from large enterprises to bring their skills up to date with modern software development tools and practices

Accomplishments

- Create and deliver curriculum on JavaScript, React, and Redux
- Facilitate the implementation of Extreme Programming style of software development
- Build applications using test-driven development
- Create REST APIs using Java and Spring Boot

Educational Software Engineer, Code Chrysalis KK

Tokyo, Japan — June 2017 - September 2017

Taught full stack JavaScript to diverse students with varying levels of programming experience

Accomplishments

- Aligned curriculum materials to learning objectives
- Evaluated and improved pre-course materials
- Designed and delivered 3-day introductory JavaScript workshops

Full Stack Developer, ThinkTank, Inc.

Denver, CO — June 2016 - June 2017

Full Stack web developer working in microservice architecture at leading edge collaboration company

Accomplishments

- Created admin app for administration of feature toggles
- Researched existing code and created recommendations for migration path
- Implemented Segment Analytics & Angular Material
- Tested with unit tests and Angular UI tests

Science Teacher, Denver Public Schools and Sheridan School District

Denver, CO — July 2006 - December 2015

Taught science for grades 7 - 12 in urban schools. Provided sheltered instruction to all levels of English Language Learners.

EDUCATION

Galvanize

Web Development Immersive Program - g19

Regis University

Master of Arts in Education, Teaching the Culturally and Linguistically Diverse

University of Colorado at Boulder

Bachelor of Arts in Chemistry, Diploma in Education